This room will be vacant
while our young master stays in Songrim.
Clean up his books and clothes.
- Yes, ma'am.
He had left home a dozen times
and returned every time.
You should wait a few days
in case he comes back again.
It is different this time.
He is a changed man.
And he may bring home a wife soon.
That is why we need to clean up.
Is he getting engaged again?
If this one falls through yet again,
he will never be able to get married.
It is different this time.
Young Master Jang has a lady
he has deep feelings for.
Right, Mu-deok?
The bird egg that he mentioned.
I believe it is that lady
I met in Songrim.
A bird egg on top of a tree.
She must be a sophisticated woman
whom he wants to protect.
She must be someone like an egret.
Like me.
Who knows?
Once it hatches,
it may turn out to be a vicious eagle,
not a sophisticated egret.
Is that so?
A vicious eagle, how frightful.
I hope it is not a woodpecker
or a cuckoo either.
Do not worry.
Once it hatches,
I am sure it will fly away.
How could she
when she has feelings for him?
If they were that close,
I am sure the feelings were mutual.
The bird must be in love with him as well.
I really hope it is Young Lady Heo.
She resembles Madam Do-hwa too.
- Mr. Lee.
- Yes?
Leave those there.
They are Master Jang's books.
Hurry up.
What Uk and I shared
was the desperate feeling of survival
and the earnestness of finding ourselves.
Once we got what we wanted,
we promised to part ways
without looking back.
The love that Maidservant Kim mentioned
may have seeped in between us.
But it is nothing but a shell
that I will leave behind once I hatch.
You have already memorized
and written all of this down?
Yes, please feel free to check.
I am certain I memorized everything.
Even so,
it should have taken you at least a month.
I have served 12 masters so far
and thus have read the same book 12 times.
You could say
that this task was a piece of cake,
to say the least.
I was wondering
why he agreed to obey the rules.
He had his reasons.
Now that I can leave Songrim
whenever I want, I will go home.
Not so fast.
Why not?
The rules say that I can leave
once I master the basic education.
When I asked you to read that,
I did not simply mean to memorize it.
I wanted you to engrave it in your heart.
But since you were sly enough
to deceive us,
I do not believe
that you have mastered this learning.
I did not know
that the leader could change
Songrim's rules however he wanted.
Here you go.
I have another task for you.
If you read this book as well,
then I will allow you
to leave Songrim whenever you wish.
No!
Are you sure that I can go outside
after reading this book?
That is right.
I hope reading this book
will be another piece of cake for you.
This is terrible.
Mu-deok will not be able
to see Uk for a while.
What? This is empty.
No, it is not.
There are words written on those papers.
No, there are not.
Do you see anything here?
It is you who cannot see.
You can only read it
once you focus your energy.
That is Master Seo Gyeong's book,
Words of the Heart,
I see.
So there are actual words on these papers?
So I am the only one who cannot read it?
Your friend, Uk,
must have not known what that book was.
He has never received proper training.
Of course he would not know.
He will be stuck in the Training Center
until he can read it.
I feel bad for him.
He will probably
be stuck there for half a year.
Even six months
would be too short for him.
He mastered Ryusu
due to pure luck, not training.
It will take him more than a year.
How do you know that
when you were never given that book?
I know you need
ample training to read that book.
Then know that he is far ahead of you.
Unlike him who received that book,
you have not touched it yet.
He is right. You should not gossip.
Bye.
Darn it.
I wonder why my uncle
gave him that book already.
I am baffled as well.
He will not be able to do anything
while he is stuck there.
I have
no intention of training Uk.
I am going to keep him near me
and check up on him
so that he will not cause
any trouble outside.
So you did not take him under your wing.
You just locked him up in Songrim.
Since Uk has entered Songrim with a fuss,
his father will be coming.
By "father", do you mean Jang Gang?
Jang Gang's biggest fear
was that Uk's gate of energy would be open
and that he would go out into the open.
Once he gets wind of this,
he will come.
The Gwanju needs to return
in order to get rid of Jin Mu.
Everything will be solved
once he returns.
I feel bad for Uk.
He came this far
without receiving any training.
How can he read Words of the Heart?
It is an impossible task.
Why would you give him these snacks?
I heard some things
about Young Master Jang.
He has a complicated family history,
barely any skills,
- and a terrible personality.
- That is not true.
He is a good man.
Why would you think that?
He is so fussy
that the only person who can put up
with him is the maid Mu-deok.
- Mu-deok?
- Yes.
She is the maid who is always by his side.
Mu-deok.
I heard you stayed by my side all night.
I thought you were Mu-deok.
I apologize for the trouble.
So that is why he thought I was her.
Hello.
We are from Sejukwon.
This way, my lady.
Wait. The fire…
Here you go.
I have another task for you.
He deceived me.
He did a number on me!
Hey, we meet again.
Hello. Are you going somewhere?
Well, yes. I need to meet someone outside.
But why are you leaving that way?
Because I am running away.
Please turn a blind eye to this as well.
My gosh. Young Lady Heo is so impatient.
Why did she not wait for me?
Why did she leave me behind?
What is the matter?
Is Jang Uk not in his room?
Yes, he is.
Let us go upstairs then.
I need to talk to him.
In private, please.
This will take some time. Wait outside.
Mu-deok, the young master
from Songrim is here.
He is looking for you.
Hello, Young Master Seo.
You must have been expecting Uk.
He will not be back for some time.
He was given a difficult task to complete.
He will do well.
It is most crucial for him to remain there
and receive training as of now.
I was concerned after how you left
that day, but you look fine.
What have you been doing?
I am just a maid here,
so I have been doing housework.
Maidservant Kim is away at the moment.
You can wait in the study.
I am here to see you, not her.
Me?
Why would you want to see me?
Well…
The umbrella.
I came to get the umbrella
I had lent you that day.
That umbrella?
The wind tore it open
on my way home, so I threw it away.
Is that so?
Then let us go.
What?
We should get a new one.
You need to buy me a new umbrella.
UMBRELLAS
This looks exactly like
the umbrella you lent me.
That is made of low-quality…
That is a disposable umbrella
made of low-quality paper.
Mine was made
from high-quality sheepskin and bamboo.
High-quality, you say?
Why did you give a maid
such an expensive umbrella?
I had only lent it to you.
You should compensate for losing it.
And that was my one and only umbrella.
Why would a young master like you
only have one umbrella?
I rarely go out when it is raining.
I had hurt my leg as a child,
and it still hurts when it rains.
Is your broken leg still giving you pain?
Young Master Park told me
about how you had broken your leg.
Yes, back in Danhyanggok.
I pity you for being a mage
who has a weak leg.
Your leg probably did not heal properly.
There was a friend
who used to wait for me in Danhyanggok.
She saved me and treated my wound.
My leg must not have healed properly
because I had not thanked her.
- I like this one.
- Pardon?
I will take this one. Go and pay for it.
Yes, Young Master Seo.
- We will take this one.
- All right.
Please put it on Master Jang Gang's tab.
Why would you do that?
You should pay for it.
A maid like me has no money.
Of course, you do.
I saw you go out
and buy clothes
with the money you keep hidden.
That was because…
- How much is it?
- You have a good eye.
That is our most expensive umbrella.
Darn it.
Mu-deok is not here?
Why did she have to be away
now of all times?
Young Master Jang,
were you kicked out again?
No, I was not.
I only stopped by for a minute.
I will be going back soon.
I see.
Mu-deok will be here soon.
Should I prepare a bath for you
in the meantime?
That sounds nice.
It has been a while
since I last bathed in this house.
- I will get it ready then.
- Sure.
Hold on.
Were our honey biscuits always this sweet?
Why does Songrim not have any snacks?
Our leader also had a sweet tooth
back in the day.
Are we breaking up today?
Yes.
The three big-mouthed sisters will be done
with their floriculture class
and will pass us by soon.
If we argue in front of them then,
they will gossip about how we broke up.
As I promised,
I will be the reason for our breakup.
First, slap me hard across my face.
Then push me away
when I cling onto you and leave.
That seems a bit extreme…
We have to go that far
for them to believe
that we really broke off our engagement.
Then people will bad-mouth you.
There will be no matchmaking for you
if you have a bad reputation.
I do not wish
to get married by matchmaking.
I will marry the woman
who I like.
Still, slapping is too much.
I will pour this on you instead.
Sure. You can do that.
The tea is too hot.
Your face will burn.
Goodness.
It is fine.
There will be a magic show in a few days.
I really wanted to watch it.
But I will not be able to
if we break up today.
Wait. Why not?
Up until now,
I stayed home for at least a month
after breaking off an engagement.
I see.
Then should we postpone
our breakup for a few days?
Should we?
But those three sisters will be there too.
I do not think I should go there alone.
Then since they think
we are a couple, I will go with you.
Well, I suppose.
I would like
some pumpkin taffy, rice taffy,
and honey biscuits.
Sure.
My young master is like a child.
He gets cranky
when there are no snacks around.
Please give them to him.
I like these pine pollen tea snacks.
I suspected you would have
expensive tastes.
- Would you like some of that too?
- No, thank you.
RECRUITING SERVANTS FOR SONGRIM
QUALIFICATIONS: HEALTHY, LITERATE,
CAN CALCULATE, NO CRIMINAL RECORD
I will put this on the Jang family's tab.
Please give these to Young Master Jang.
I have some business
to take care of. Goodbye.
Here you go.
- Have a look around.
- I will.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Goodbye.
It is her, right?
It is her.
Hey.
- You took my purse, right?
- Give me back my ring.
- Goodness!
- Where is she?
- Hey! Stop right there!
- Hey!
Stop right there!
- You!
- Stop that swindler!
- Thief!
- Hey, come back here!
- Goodness!
- Just wait until I get my hands on you!
- Hey! Stop!
- Wait for me!
- Darn it.
- Hey!
- Hurry up!
- What are you doing?
You little…
Catch that swindler!
- She got away.
- Hey.
- That is her, right?
- Yes.
That is Mu-deok.
Mu-deok!
There you are, you…
- You.
- Catch that thief!
Come here.
Wait until I get my hands on you.
Hey!
You little…
It was definitely her.
But how can she see now?
She had always covered her eyes with this.
Was it not her?
We finally meet again,
So-i.
I went all the way to Sari Village
because I heard you were there.
But you were long gone.
Did you think hiding
in the capital would work?
What is this?
Were you pretending to be blind?
But then again,
you did put up a nice, pitiful front.
Then you would betray others
behind their backs.
How dare you steal
my money?
I do not know what you are--
Jeez…
Look at you trying to deceive me again.
Take her.
Help me!
Somebody, please help me!
I am blind!
I do not know them,
yet they are trying to kidnap me!
Someone, please help me!
Look at you trying real hard.
Please help me!
What are you all looking at?
- Come here.
- Let me go!
You cannot drag her against her will.
I have a good reason for doing this,
so just go on your way.
I cannot see,
- and I do not know who they are.
- You little--
Get him!
He is a mage.
Let us go!
Can you stand?
Thank you.
They look like dangerous men.
You should ask the authorities for help.
I will take you there.
That is all right.
I do not need their help.
Your cane is broken.
This is an umbrella.
You can use this as a cane.
Master, it is best to just let her be.
She refused to be taken
to the authorities.
I do not know what kind of past she has,
but those were thugs.
Nothing good will come out
of involving yourself in their affairs.
I will take you there.
You should ask the authorities for help.
Maybe I should have said yes.
Number 125.
Did these many people
already sign up for it?
ONE HUNDRED TWENTY-FIVE
They are only picking five people.
Do I have hope?
Hey, Mu-deok.
Were you here all along?
The young master was looking for you.
Did Young Master Seo come by again?
Not him. Young Master Jang.
Young Master Jang snuck out
and has come home.
I need to go back before sundown.
Where in the world is she?
Where is Young Master Jang?
He just left,
but I did not see him either.
He said he would be obedient,
so why did he escape?
I hope he does not get caught.
He just left.
Just now.
What is with her?
Jang Uk.
Young Master!
Where have you been?
I thought I would not get to see you.
I finally got to see you. I am glad.
I need to go.
They cannot know that I am gone.
Wait there. I will go to you soon.
I found a way,
so do what you need to do in there.
I will do what I can out here.
All right. But what way is that?
Songrim is hiring.
Do not get caught and get back safely.
Your Royal Highness,
instead of going to Sejukwon yourself,
you should summon
Master Heo to your palace.
That is all right.
It gives me a reason to come out.
I like taking strolls.
Is that not Jang Uk?
Why are you out here?
I heard you could not leave
the Training Center
until you could read Words of the Heart.
Not only did you follow me
to where I was drinking,
but you are also keeping tabs on me.
Why are you so interested in me?
It is making me uncomfortable.
Master Heo from Sejukwon told me.
Right. I heard you fell ill
after drinking the liquor I had given you.
Then why did you come to Sejukwon?
Does it still hurt where I hit you?
Oh, dear.
Not at all. I am all better now.
I only go there to get some supplements.
I hope you take many good supplements.
You must live a long, healthy life.
What were you hiding just a while ago?
Let me see it.
It is a honey biscuit.
I wanted to eat it for myself.
How did you know?
You can have it.
Songrim does not have
these kinds of snacks.
Did you go home?
You will be in trouble
if they find out you have sneaked out.
You even gave me a congratulatory drink
and complimented me.
Will you seriously tattle on me
for this little misdeed?
After all, I even gave you
that honey biscuit.
Stay away from that big pine tree.
I saw a group of mages there.
Thank you, Your Royal Highness. Goodbye.
I do not understand
why I am being nice to him.
This is tasty.
Is it?
- Is it tasty, Your Royal Highness?
- Yes.
I thought the Crown Prince
would be hostile
toward Songrim after the match.
Rather, he has sheathed his sword
and become closer to them.
He must have decided to befriend them
so that they could be of use
when he becomes the next king.
Are you sure we do not need
to do anything about it?
Do not worry.
We can easily change his mind.
We have Jang Uk's constellation plate.
The Crown Prince will have no choice
but to kill him eventually.
Is that what we will use
to subdue Jin Ho-gyeong?
Jinyowon will be ours soon.
It has been four hours
since Young Lady Heo went inside.
Do not bother them.
They must have a lot to talk about.
Hey! Wait!
You should not bother them.
Something is not right.
I must check whether or not
Jang Uk is in there.
Are you doubting my lady?
Gosh.
Why is he not here yet?
It will be awkward
if they find out he is not here.
Why are you here? What are you doing?
I told them we were in here together
so they would not catch you leaving.
I have been waiting for your return.
See? They are together.
I will go now.
I had a great chat with you today.
Likewise.
Goodbye.
What were you doing here
for the past four hours?
Beats me.
What were we doing here for that long?
She must have been bored.
You want to become a servant of Songrim?
Yes, ma'am. Look what happened today.
Young Master Jang needs me
by his side at all times.
I agree.
He must have been so uncomfortable
that he came here to bathe and eat snacks.
Our young master is very sensitive
and has been doted on growing up.
Living with others in Songrim
does not suit him.
ONE HUNDRED TWENTY-FIVE
I already signed up.
I will get in at all costs.
Hey, you do not need that.
This is the Jang family.
We can easily put you in there.
Is that true?
Does that mean
I do not need to take the test?
Of course not. Just trust me.
That is not possible.
Songrim's servants are only chosen
through open recruitments.
There is no exception.
I am not asking you
to give her a free position.
She just needs the entrance plaque.
Just register her name
so she can get one.
We will pay you monthly.
Also…
Here.
I thought it would suit you,
so I got you one, Maidservant Park.
Here.
Word has it that you bribed
Maidservant Park of Songrim with this.
- It was purely a gift…
- I heard you asked her
to give Mu-deok a spot there.
Since our young master is so sensitive,
I thought having Mu-deok by his side
would help him with his training,
so I asked for a favor.
So this truly was a bribe!
I apologize. It was thoughtless of me.
When Maidservant Park brought this to me,
I vehemently told her
that you were not one to do such a thing.
I defended you.
How will I dare face her ever again?
I…
I will apologize to her.
What will everyone think?
They will think you abused
your relationship with me
to bribe someone.
I did give her that scarf,
but I never mentioned you to her.
Even so,
everyone in Songrim knows
that you and I are close.
If you do this, I can no longer…
have a close relationship with you.
In that case, I will stop coming here.
And what did you say?
Was our relationship ever that deep?
If we were truly close,
you would not have mentioned
cutting ties with me so easily.
Fine.
- Maidservant Kim, I…
- I will tell Maidservant Park
that I, who bribes people,
am not close
with the leader of Songrim even one bit.
- Look--
- All right.
I am terribly sorry
that I made you lose face.
Maidservant Kim.
You cannot just leave like that.
Take this.
I would be accepting this bribe
if I were to keep it.
Also…
I did not mean
that I did not want you to come…
Maid--
Maidservant Kim!
This is difficult.
You cannot do it yet.
Master Lee.
You cannot read that book
with the concentration you have now.
You have never trained diligently
like the others have.
How long will it take
if I start training now?
The earliest would be in a year.
I cannot do that. I refuse
to be stuck in here for that long.
I think that is exactly the reason
why Park Jin gave you that book.
You could shorten that time
if you become my pupil
and receive my teachings.
Do you mean
by drinking that chaste herb tea?
Please give me some time to think.
This book contains my master,
Master Seo Gyeong's poem.
Poem?
It is not that long.
Once you read the first word,
the rest will come easily to you.
Right. You cannot read this yet, can you?
Are you having fun teasing me?
It is not like you will tell me.
It is quite entertaining to watch.
Shall I help you again this time?
Yes, please.
Let me tell you one secret
about this book that no one knows of.
This poem is actually a love letter.
A love letter?
That is right.
Countless mages have read this,
but no one knows that fact.
Master Seo Gyeong wrote this
for a lady who could not see
so that she could read it with her heart.
You can read it by training
your concentration skills.
But try to think of another way
since I told you it was a love letter.
How does a love letter begin?
What is this?
Was he a pervert?
Why would he make others
read his love letter?
Why must I read this?
It is invisible to me.
Was he really a pervert?
Master Lee, it is getting colder now.
Instead of returning to Danhyanggok,
how about you stay here?
I will treat you well.
Yeom.
I cannot train by wearing warm clothes
and feeling comfortable.
I am just a pupil
who wants his master to be warm.
I guess you have matured with age.
That is Maidservant Kim
from the Jang family.
Seeing how she looks unhappy,
she must have fought with Jin again.
Goodness. Hello.
Master Lee.
Why did you leave so quickly last time?
I did not have the chance to thank you.
Have you two met before?
We met at the party in Chwiseonru.
How are your clothes?
I made your seam run.
I am fine.
Seam?
I see.
It is very cold.
Do you not feel cold in those clothes?
Wear this.
I wanted to get you a thank-you gift.
This is a gift, not a bribe.
Here.
It suits you.
Will you be all right wearing that?
SONGRIM SERVANT CONTEST
We will now begin
the Songrim Servant Contest
and pick those of you
who will work in Songrim.
I will read the name list.
Answer me when I call your names.
Number one, Park Jun-hwa.
Here.
Number two, An So-jeong.
Here!
An So-jeong.
TWO
An…
- Number three, Lee Yeong-ok.
- Here.
- Number four, Park Hyeon-su.
- Number five, Bae Hui-young.
- Here.
What is this?
I am looking at it just in case.
ONE HUNDRED TWENTY-FIVE, MU-DEOK
There you are.
Number 125, Mu-deok.
Over here!
Your maid, Mu-deok, is in Songrim today.
Let me warn you in advance.
Do not try to leave this room.
Can you keep it down…
Could you be quiet, please?
I need all the concentration
I can get to read this.
I will let you be then.
I will see you again in three days,
Your Royal Highness.
Why is Songrim so busy today?
It is teeming with people.
They are holding a contest
to pick out some servants.
- Do they need to turn it into a contest?
- Your Royal Highness.
Many people
want to work here as a servant.
I saw the maid from the Jang family too.
- Filthy Mu-deok?
- Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Your first test
will require you to read and calculate.
You must get all of them right.
One wrong answer,
and you will be disqualified!
SONGRIM SERVANT CONTEST
Yul!
I found the test papers.
There are many questions.
Even short-answer ones.
Mu-deok is smart,
but will she get them all right?
This is pretty difficult?
Eunuch Oh, what do you need
to wash clothes that have ink on them?
That is a question here.
Rice paste does the trick.
What do you do with it?
First, you apply it on…
SONGRIM SERVANT CONTEST
"You invited 20 individuals each
from 3 different families."
"One table can seat four people.
How many tables do you need?"
Twenty individuals from three families
mean sixty in total.
Since one table can fit four of them,
- it is fifteen.
- No.
They said "three families" on purpose.
Those from the same family
must sit together.
We need more tables
if they will be placed together.
Each family would need nine tables.
That is 27 in total.
This was an invitation.
NINE × THREE = TWENTY-SEVEN
The host needs a table as well.
TWENTY-SEVEN + HOST
= TWENTY…
Twenty-eight in total.
You are right.
TWENTY-EIGHT
Next question is about running errands
and not getting lost.
Let me get a map of the capital.
HOW DO YOU WASH CLOTHES
THAT HAVE INK ON THEM?
What should you do
if there is ink on the clothes?
Should you not just dispose of them?
Eunuch Oh.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
How do you wash clothes
that have ink on them again?
You need some warm rice paste.
- Smear it on the--
- That is right.
Write it.
"Warm rice paste."
SONGRIM SERVANT CONTEST
We probably got all of them right.
I did not expect to do this with you,
but it was fun.
I can assure you that Mu-deok will fail.
That is why we should deliver
this perfect test paper to her.
But how can we do that?
It will look too obvious if we do it.
Perhaps someone who is more conspicuous
will avoid suspicion.
SONGRIM SERVANT CONTEST
This is hard.
This is more difficult than I thought.
Do not look at other people's papers.
The Crown Prince is here! Bow before him!
Goodness. Your Royal Highness!
- Your Royal Highness!
I heard there was an important test,
so I wanted to encourage you.
We are honored to have you here.
Do not mind me and focus on the test.
Focus!
- You too.
- Focus--
Get back to what you were doing.
I will now announce
those of you who have passed.
Park Jun-hwa, you have passed.
Lee Yeong-ok, failed.
Hwang Yeon-ji, failed.
Oh Jae-ho, you have passed.
Number 125.
Mu-deok.
Your Royal Highness!
She got in!
Yes!
Good work.
Forty of you have passed the first test.
Now comes the practical test.
The practical test
will evaluate them on their duties.
They will prepare ingredients,
clean, and wash clothes.
Lastly, there will be a fitness test.
Number 125, Mu-deok.
You have passed.
You have passed!
ONE HUNDRED TWENTY-FIVE
Number 125, Mu-deok.
You have passed!
Gosh, Mu-deok is impressive.
Now, it is the fitness test.
We should go and cheer for her.
I saw many fit individuals back there.
I highly doubt she will be
one of the last five.
Your Royal Highness,
thank you for helping us.
Goodbye.
- Let us go.
- All right.
That was his way of telling me
not to come, right?
Goodness, why did they have to be so mean?
Unbelievable.
Forget it. Let us go.
Your Royal Highness, it is this way.
- I know.
- Of course, Your Royal Highness.
You will travel five ri
and bring back some water.
Those who are the first five
to arrive will be the final winners.
This is the last hurdle.
I must be in the first five.
Go!
He has been looking
at Words of the Heart for days on end.
Is that so?
It will not happen that soon.
Have patience.
Yes, my lord.
Maidservant Kim is worried sick about you.
Let me know if you need anything.
I will prepare your bed, food,
and clothes to your liking.
I am fine.
The wind is getting chillier now.
Keep the windows closed.
Master Seo Gyeong wrote this
for a lady who could not see
so that she could read it with her heart.
I have one question.
Did Master Seo Gyeong know
of a woman who could not see?
During the Great Chaos
that occurred 200 years ago,
the first leader of Jinyowon
was the one who helped
Master Seo Gyeong by his side.
And she could not see.
He had written this love letter
for the leader of Jinyowon.
By the way, are you sure
you can let others read this?
What if these are his private thoughts
that you are making everyone read?
You must be trying to use me
to read what is written in there.
I will tell you this.
Those words have nothing to do
with his private thoughts.
Countless mages have read this,
but no one knows that fact.
Right. No one knows
that it is a love letter.
Instead of coming up with tricks,
you should focus more
on training yourself.
How could no one know
that this is a love letter?
You can read it by training
your concentration skills.
But try to think of another way
since I told you it was a love letter.
There must be a different way
to read this love letter.
Those who read this
through training do not know.
Only those who are aware
that it is a love letter can read it.
But how?
How does a love letter begin?
I have one last question.
What was the name
of the first leader of Jinyowon?
All love letters begin
with the recipient's name.
Her surname
was Jin, and her first name was Seol-ran.
The recipient's name was Seol-ran.
"An orchid that blooms
in the white snow."
Her name
will open this letter.
YOU CANNOT GRASP WATER
BUT IT IS INSIDE THE SOIL
I can read it.
Hey, there she is.
There is Mu-deok.
"You cannot grasp water,
but it is inside the soil."
"You cannot touch fire,
but it is inside the tree."
"You cannot hold the wind,
but it is resting on the rock."
"If you let them be,
they will exist everywhere."
"The faint, blue light
makes me sigh."
"My white breath
turned into snow and tears."
"I could not let them drop and hid them."
"Despite knowing that
they will fill up once again,
I am a fool
who dares not shed a single tear."
Those two are already back.
I do not see Mu-deok.
There are six people in front of Mu-deok.
She needs to beat
at least two of them to win.
I AM A FOOL
WHO DARES NOT SHED A SINGLE TEAR
YOU CANNOT GRASP WATER
BUT IT IS INSIDE THE SOIL
Where are you going?
Right.
I read it.
Number 29,
Jang Jeong-do. You have passed.
Only one more remains.
I do not need a pupil
who does not improve.
Just die if you are
not going to do anything.
Hey! That is dangerous!
You are no longer Naksu.
No matter how pathetic you feel,
you must do what you can at the moment.
If I am not willing to do anything,
I might as well just die.
Number 125, Mu-deok.
You have passed!
YOU CANNOT GRASP WATER
BUT IT IS INSIDE THE SOIL
It is exactly identical
to Words of the Heart.
Jang Uk accomplished the task.
He accomplished the task?
- Where is he right now?
- He is at Sejukwon.
The maid who was always with him
collapsed while taking the test,
so he took her there.
His maid?
- Do you mean Mu-deok?
- Yes, my lord.
She passed the test today.
She did pass out at the finish line,
but she did indeed make it.
Is that so?
My maid only risked her life
by doing what she was told to do.
It was all my doing.
Now that I think of it,
she was always beside Uk.
His maid, Mu-deok…
The book that I read was actually
Master Seo Gyeong's love letter.
Really?
Then why did he make it invisible?
The woman could not see.
He wanted her to read with her heart.
How wistful.
I do not think
the letter was sent.
If it was, it would have been in Jinyowon,
not Songrim.
An invisible love letter
that was never sent?
What a coward.
He wrote down his feelings
without her knowing.
What a foolish
and pitiful love letter.
You are right. He should have…
delivered the letter like you did.
RECRUITING SERVANTS FOR SONGRIM
That is not a letter.
What is there to a letter?
As long as it delivers your feelings.
Wait there. I will go to you soon.
Do not get caught and get back safely.
You must have pitied me
for trying to get in here as a servant.
You used to be
an incredibly experienced master.
I did feel bad for you.
I guess I helped you learn
about loyalty and duties.
Seeing how far you would go as my master,
I did think that I should do my best.
You must have felt pressured.
Not really. But I was in a dilemma.
I did not know if I should reply
as your young master or pupil.
Or just reply based on what I read.
What did you read?
Then should I also reply
based on what I read?
Also? What do you mean?
It is written here.
"I will go this far just to see you."
"I can do anything
if it means being able to see you."
And this is my reply.
I should have braced myself
before letting him get this close to me.
I also missed you.
That is my reply.
What I gave him
should not have been read
or delivered in the first place.
It was my foolish and pathetic
love letter.
I miss you first thing in the morning,
- all throughout the day--
- Stop.
It is a terrible poison you cannot escape,
as its only antidote is
the person it is from.
Are you out of your mind?
This is just a symptom.
I have been poisoned.
So the only one in your mind
has been Jang Uk, Naksu.
You did not believe me
when I said I was in love with you.
Then do a better job
and make me believe it.
That is the most precious object
I have ever received.
Please do your best
so you can win it back.
I have made a bet with your maid, Mu-deok.
Fight and perish, Jang Uk.
When I said I missed you,
is this what you meant
when you said you had my weakness?
Do not go.
I like Mu-deok a lot.
Subtitle translation by: Soo-ji Kim